{"tossups": [{"question": "One of this ruler\u2019s defeats inspired a man called the Master of Hungary to launch the Shepherds\u2019Crusade. With James I of Aragon, this ruler signed the Treaty of Corbeil. He suppressed the rebel Hugh of Lusignan at the Battle of Taillebourg. This subject of a biography by Jean de Joinville was defeated at the Battle of Fariskur, part of a campaign in which he captured Damietta but failed to conquer Egypt. For ten points, name this leader of the Seventh Crusade, the only French king to be canonized.", "answer": "<b> Louis IX</b> [9] (accept<b> Saint Louis</b>; prompt on Louis)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Ron Walters led the push to desegregate this state\u2019s Dockum Drug Store lunch counters in 1958. In the 1850s, Benjamin Singleton helped make this state\u2019s community of Nicodemus and the surrounding area become the destination of many newly freed African American migrants called Exodusters. In the 1950s, 13 families in this state\u2019s capital city sued to be allowed to attend Sumner Elementary and other schools. For ten points, name this state where Oliver Brown and others sued the Board of Education of Topeka.", "answer": "<b> Kansas</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Panicked police officers fired their weapons during this event, probably because of an earlier incident in which nine constables died at Cato Manor. UN Resolution 134 was passed after this event, which constituted \u201cgross human rights violations\u201d according to the Truth and Reconciliation Commission. Umkhonto we Sizwe, the military wing of the ANC, was founded in the wake of this event, which occurred after Hendrik Verwoerd expanded apartheid policies. Protesters against the Pass Laws were shot in, for ten points, what 1960 massacre in what is now Gauteng in South Africa?", "answer": "<b> Sharpeville</b> Massacre Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Several workers hired to create this route were killed in a raid on Martin\u2019s Station. A notable portion of what would become this route was first crossed by a European after Gabriel Arthur was captured by the Shawnee. Speculator Richard Henderson founded the Transylvania Company, which was tasked with creating this route starting at Fort Chiswell. Farm supplies were brought to what became the future states of Kentucky and Tennessee via, for ten points, what road that passed through the Cumberland Gap and was blazed by Daniel Boone?", "answer": "<b> Wilderness Road</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A now-ruined building in this city named Etemenanki may have been destroyed by Sennacherib. A set of remains decorated with aurochs and blue bricks that was relocated from this city was reconstructed in the Pergamon Museum in Berlin. While drinking from vessels stolen from the first temple, a king of this city stares at a disembodied hand and illuminated Hebrew letters in Rembrandt\u2019s painting of<em> Belshezzar\u2019s</em> <em>Feast</em>. The Ishtar Gate led to the inner part of, for ten points, what city that contained a temple to Marduk and was led by King Nebuchadnezzar?", "answer": "<b> Babylon</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This leader passed the<em> Rosatellum</em> law to reform electoral politics and abolished labor vouchers after pressure from the CGIL union. The 2017 G7 summit was hosted by this leader, who faced pressure from the Northern League and Five Star Movement in a recent election. Sergio Mattarella appointed this man to his highest post in December 2016, but dissolved his Parliament just over a year later. Matteo Renzi was succeeded by, for ten points, what Prime Minister of Italy who announced his resignation in March 2018?", "answer": "Paolo<b> Gentiloni</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this deadly hurricane that struck Florida in 1992.", "answer": "Hurricane<b> Andrew</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this modern-day country, Nikola Karev briefly led the breakaway Kru\u02c7sevo Republic against the Ottoman Empire. The Treaty of Ni\u02c7s [neess] forced Bulgarian Prime Minister Aleksandar Stamboliyski to crack down on the activities of IMRO, a group named for this country; IMRO captured and assassinated him. This country is officially recognized under the acronym FYROM due to a naming dispute with its southern neighbor. For ten points, name this southernmost of the former constituent countries of Yugoslavia, a country that shares its name with a region in Northern Greece.", "answer": "<b> Macedonia</b> (accept<b> F</b>ormer<b> Y</b>ugoslav<b> R</b>epublic<b> o</b>f<b> M</b>acedonia before \u201cFYROM\u201d is read; do not accept Macedon) Page 3", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2005, this man defeated Mariano Puerta, who was later found to be doping, to win his first major. Several achievements of this man have merited the name \u201cLa D\u00b4ecima,\u201d because he has won at least ten times at tournaments such as Barcelona. This winner of the 2008 men\u2019s singles Olympic gold medal beat Bjorn Borg\u2019s record of winning 16 titles as a teenager and surpassed Borg\u2019s record at a tournament in Paris. For ten points, name this \u201cKing of Clay,\u201d a Spanish tennis player who has won the French Open a record 10 times.", "answer": "Rafael<b> Nadal</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A plaque on this island commemorating the Reunion of Honor claimed that the sacrifices on it \u201cwill always be remembered and never be repeated.\u201d Bernardo de la Torre was the first European to reach this member of the Bonin Archipelago, which he named after the Spanish word for sulphur. Michael Strank, Franklin Sousley, and Harlon Block died on this island days after being recorded in a Pulitzer Prize-winning photograph. For ten points, name this island whose Mount Suribachi was the site of a 1945 flag raising by American Marines.", "answer": "<b> Iwo Jima</b> (accept<b> Iwo To</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Izola Curry stopped a man from speaking in this city during the 1st Youth March. A speech given in this city asserts that a certain group, \u201cwill quietly and nonviolently\u201d help \u201cimplement the Supreme Court\u2019s decision of May 17, 1954.\u201d During the Prayer Pilgrimage, the \u201cGive Us the Ballot\u201d speech was delivered in this city. Walter Reuther helped support an event in this city, where the Big Six spoke. Bayard Rustin and Asa Philip Randolph organized a 1963 March on, for ten points, what city where Martin Luther King delivered the \u201cI Have a Dream\u201d speech?", "answer": "Washington<b> D.C.</b> (accept<b> Washington</b>; accept<b> District of Columbia</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Matthew Scrivener briefly led this colony, but drowned with several others on a crossing to Hog Island. A leader of this settlement issued a \u201cRude Answer\u201d to the Earls of Southampton and Salisbury, who questioned why this colony was a financial disaster. The<em> Godspeed</em>,<em> Discovery</em>, and captain Christopher Newport\u2019s<em> Susan Constant</em> landed at this settlement, which was later led by John Smith. For ten points, name this first permanent English settlement established in Virginia.", "answer": "<b> Jamestown</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Augustine Podmore Williams scandalously abandoned a group of participants in one of these events to die on an abandoned ship in a hurricane, inspiring Joseph Conrad\u2019s novel<em> Lord Jim</em>. Iranian diplomat Ghazanfar Roknabadi died during this event in the 2015 Mina Stampede. During this event, participants throw pebbles at the<em> jamarat</em>, representing the Devil. Travelers walk around the Kaaba seven times counter-clockwise as part of, for ten points, what Muslim pilgrimage to Mecca?", "answer": "<b> Hajj</b> (prompt on pilgrimage before mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This project ironically contributed to a concentration of working class socialist supporters in Belleville, an effect of skyrocketing rent. As part of this project, large glass and steel</b> <b>pavilions were designed by Victor (+)</b> <b>Baltard and placed at Les Halles [lay hall]. A map</b> <b>produced for this project featured three dark, straight lines and was presented to a former Prefect of Bordeaux; the maker of that map was partially inspired by (*)</b> Hyde Park in London to complete this project. The Prefect of the Seine oversaw, for ten points, what mid-19th century project that obliterated much of the \u02c6Ile-de-Cit\u00b4e [eel de lah see-tay], widened streets, and modernized Napoleon III\u2019s capital?", "answer": "Baron Georges-Eug`ene<b> Haussmann\u2019s renovation of Paris</b> (accept descriptions of<b> the renovation of Paris under Napoleon III</b> until his name is read, but do not prompt on Napoleon alone in that answer; accept equivalent terms for \u201crenovation;\u201d prompt on partial answers) (2) <b>After David S. Jackson was unseated for election fraud, this man was selected to</b> <b>replace him in a special election. This man wrote \u201cWe defy it, execrate it, spit upon it\u201d in response to Winfield Scott\u2019s unpopular platform. In 1872, Georgia\u2019s (+) electoral votes for this Liberal Republican candidate were rejected. This man employed Whitelaw Reid and Margaret Fuller at a newspaper that printed this man\u2019s (*)</b> \u201cPrayer of Twenty Millions\u201d in 1862. For ten points, name this founder of the<em> New York Tribune</em> who popularized the phrase \u201cGo West, young man\u201d and died shortly after losing the 1872 presidential election. ANSWER: Horace<b> Greeley</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The original manuscript of this work was taken by British soldiers after they captured the Old South Meeting House\u2019s tower, where it was held. Samuel Eliot Morison wrote a preface to this work in which he claimed that it made its central subjects \u201cthe spiritual (+) ancestors of all Americans.\u201d This work, a series of journal articles made between 1630 and 1651, notably omits any mention of a disembarkation from a (*) </b> rock and ends by listing the passengers of the<em> Mayflower</em>. For ten points, name this text that details the early history of the Pilgrims, written by William Bradford.", "answer": "<b> Of Plymouth Plantation</b> (accept<b> History of Plymouth Plantation</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>During the trial following this event, Mose Wright dramatically identified John William Milam among the crowd. William Huie interviewed the perpetrators of this event for</b><em><b> Look</b></em> <b>magazine in exchange for 4,000 dollars. (+)</b> <b>Carolyn Bryant testified that the victim of</b> <b>this event wolf-whistled at her; the victim\u2019s mother, Mamie, remarked that he whistled to overcome his stutter. Mamie insisted on an open-casket funeral for this event\u2019s victim after his body was found in the (*)</b> Tallahatchie River, after which a photograph of his body was printed in<em> The Chicago Defender</em>. For ten points, name this 1955 murder of a black teenager in Mississippi.", "answer": "<b> murder</b> (or<b> lynching</b>,<b> shooting</b>, etc.) of Emmett<b> Till</b> (only<b> Till</b> is needed after \u201cmurder\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In this war, D\u00b4amaso Berenguer used \u201csuffocating gas\u201d with \u201ctrue joy\u201d after a supposed treachery of the indigenous people. One country\u2019s monarchy lost political support after this war\u2019s Disaster of Annual which helped spark a 1923 coup led by (+) Primo de Rivera. After French outposts along the Oureghla [wear-g\u2019lah] River were attacked in this war, the French intervened on the side of a fellow European nation. The city of (*)</b> Melilla was spared during this war on the orders of Abd el-Krim. For ten points, name this 1920s war in which Spain defeated a breakaway republic in northern Morocco.", "answer": "<b> Rif</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The speaker of a poem written for this type of event says \u201cMy life belongs to the world. I will do what I can.\u201d James Dickey\u2019s \u201cThe Strength of Fields\u201d was written for this type of event. Another poem written for one of these events introduces the symbols of \u201cA (+) Rock, A River, A Tree\u201d and states that, \u201cNo less to Midas than the mendicant,\u201d America is \u201cyour country.\u201d Another poem read at this type of event opens \u201cThe (*) </b> land was ours before we were the land\u2019s.\u201d For ten points, name this type of event where Maya Angelou\u2019s \u201cOn the Pulse of Morning\u201d and Robert Frost\u2019s \u201cThe Gift Outright\u201d were read in Washington, D.C.", "answer": "U.S. Presidential<b> inauguration</b> ceremonies (accept Jimmy Carter\u2019s<b> inauguration</b>; accept Bill Clinton\u2019s<b> inauguration</b> after \u201cA Rock\u201d is read; accept John Kennedy\u2019s<b> inauguration</b> after \u201cThe land\u201d is read) Page 12", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>While representing the cousin of Dada Abdullah, this man left a court after being asked to remove his turban. This man presented a petition with 10,000 signatures to Lord Ripon,</b> <b>convincing him to temporarily suspend the Natal Assembly. Hermann (+)</b> <b>Kallenbach</b> <b>donated the land that allowed this man to establish Tolstoy Farm. In a 1906 article, this man outlined his \u201cloyalty to the truth,\u201d an idea that evolved into (*) </b> Satyagraha. For ten points, name this activist whose poor treatment in South Africa helped convince him to fight for Indian independence.", "answer": "<b> M</b>ohandas<b> Gandhi</b> (accept<b> M</b>ahatma<b> Gandhi</b>; prompt on Gandhi)  (1) <b>Cable 243 authorized a coup after a government\u2019s suppression of these people.</b> <b>Journalists covering the persecution of these people included Peter Arnett and Malcolm Browne, both of whom were targeted by secret police on Double Seven Day. The term (+) \u201cbarbecue\u201d was derisively used by Madame Nhu to describe the actions</b> <b>of one of these people, (*)</b> Thich Quang Duc [thik kwang dook], who had self-immolated to protest the regime of Ngo Dinh Diem [no din dee-em]. For ten points, name this religious group whose pagodas were often raided by South Vietnamese police. ANSWER:<b> Buddhists</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}